In this tutorial video, we use the 11th version of DOS Marvelous Designer.
If you need to learn the 10th version of Marvelous Designer, please watch the quick introduction video released before.
In order to make it easier to learn, DOS is used in this tutorial.
When using Marvelous Designer, you can draw the board in 2D or 3D windows.
In this tutorial video, you will learn how to make a T-shirt mountain in 3D windows.
By drawing the board in 3D windows, you can determine the basic shape of the board,
which helps you to learn the course of drawing boards in 2D windows.
Drawing boards in 3D windows directly helps you to create basic costumes quickly for your unique virtual model.
First, we need to introduce a virtual model.
Here we have a virtual model.
We will open the Vimeo VR file folder.
Select the 3D model tool and select the virtual model tool in the drop-down menu.
Click on the middle point in the foreground to create a starting point.
Then move the mouse to draw the front and middle lines.
Press the Shift key to draw a line along the horizontal or vertical direction.
Press the left mouse button in the right position.
Continue to press the Shift key to move the mouse to preview the line.
Press the left mouse button in the left position of the horizontal line.
Continue to move the mouse to draw the side line.
Since the model's waist line is a curve, we need to create a curve on the horizontal line.
Press the left mouse button in the right position to create a curve.
This is the curve.
Release the Ctrl key and press the left mouse button in the lower position to create a straight line.
Complete the drawing of the horizontal line.
Next, we will draw a curve along the sleeve.
Remember to press the Ctrl key to create a curve.
Release the Ctrl key and press the right mouse button in the left position to create a straight line.
After the curve is created, press the Shift key and click on the mouse button to create a shoulder line.
Continue to draw a curve and then click on the starting point to complete the drawing of the template.
Before we remove the template from the 2D window, we need to set the front, middle, bottom, and shoulder lines as straight lines.
Change the tool to Edit Line Virtual Model.
Right-click on these 3D lines and select Edit Line as Straight Line.
The line that is edited as a straight line will be displayed as a thicker line.
Select the mouse and select the Edit Line tool in the drop-down menu.
Select the mouse in the created template area.
Move the mouse to click on the mouse when the area changes to blue.
After selecting, the area changes to yellow. Press the Enter key to extract the template.
Now the front will be extracted to the 2D window.
Now we create the back of the template in the same way.
I will start drawing from the highest point of the shoulder, then draw the back, middle, waist, and shoulder line.
First, draw the back.
Press the Shift key and click on the mouse button to draw the back, middle, and then complete the bottom line along the vertical direction.
Click on the side point created before and complete the bottom creation.
Since the side line has been drawn, I am now going to draw the shoulder line.
Start from the bottom point that has been drawn.
Draw a curve along the virtual model body curve.
Click on the side point to complete the creation.
Same as the front, set the back, middle, and bottom lines as a straight line.
Next is the sleeve version.
Start from the side point on the outside.
Draw a straight line as the sleeve middle line according to your needs.
Press the Ctrl key along the arm circle to draw the sleeve bottom line.
Continue to draw the inside edge of the sleeve until it is connected to the bottom point.
Repeat the operation to complete the other half of the sleeve version.
After completion, select the Edit line virtual model tool.
Set the sleeve middle line to a flat straight line.
Then select the flat as a version tool.
Click on two areas of the sleeve version to remove it as a version.
Now the sleeve version on one side is completed.
We need to adjust some lines more smoothly.
Select the Edit version of the sleeve tool and press the E key.
Press the Shift key to click on the two straight lines in the center of the front.
At the same time, click on the right button at the bottom to select the right axis.
The front will become a vertical line.
In the same way, select the two straight lines at the bottom.
In the right-hand menu, select the right axis.
The lower line of the X-axis will become a horizontal line in the 2D window.
Adjust the back piece in the same way.
In the right-hand menu, select the right axis.
In the left-hand menu, select the right axis.
For the sleeve version, we need to rotate them first to the right position, then the parallel version.
Change to the adjustment version tool.
Right-click on the sleeve version and select Rotate.
The mouse is located on a line.
You can see that the rotation of this line and the rotation of the y-axis are parallel.
Click on the release effect of the version to complete the rotation.
Now let's modify the inner line of the sleeve and the bottom.
On the edit version tool, select the mouse.
You can find the edit curve point and the edit element tool in the drop-down menu.
Select the edit curve point tool or press the V key,
then select the inner line once, the curve point on the bottom,
and delete them with the Delete key.
Select the edit version tool or press the Z key.
Repeat the previous operation to remove the inner line and the bottom of the sleeve.
Now we will learn how to merge two versions into one version.
Select the middle line of the two versions,
then right-click on the selected line and select Merge.
Please note that after merging, the original line will no longer exist.
Now let's adjust the sleeve curve and the sleeve mountain curve of the mountain.
Select the edit curve point and press the V key,
select the edit curve point tool,
refer to the video, delete the useless curve point,
and keep the sleeve curve line as an O curve.
Then use the edit original curve tool,
refer to the version in the video, drag the sleeve curve line to the appropriate curve.
Use the same method to adjust the sleeve mountain curve line.
In this way, one side of the sleeve curve is moreบ,
and one side is less 0.
On the right-hand side of the version that has been adjusted, select and .
After using this function, the version created will be synchronized with the original version.
The line will be symmetrical.
Please place the version in the 2D window.
Use the same method to create a symmetrical version of the sleeve and the back.
Next is the pocket version of the chest.
Select the 3D version tool in the 3D tool bar.
Draw a rectangular pocket line according to the need.
Then switch to the 3D version tool in the edit point line in the download menu.
Select all the lines that form the pocket.
Click and select the inner shape of the collage.
The pocket line will be created on two front pieces at the same time.
Because they are in a symmetrical relationship, select the edit curve tool to delete the excess curve points.
Adjust the pocket to a symmetrical rectangular shape.
We will later extract the pocket version of the sewing box based on this rectangular shape.
The mouse is attached to the edit version tool group.
In the download menu, select the collage outline tool.
Select the rectangular shape in the box and click the selected pattern on the right.
Select the collage as a version.
Please note that the collage as a version does not have a link function.
What is extracted is an independent version.
Now we have completed the creation of a set of T-shirt versions.
Please save this project as a project file.
We will use this project file in the future teaching video.